Hello everyone and welcome
to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today
we have a very special lesson for you.
This is actually the first in a series
of lessons about interview skills.
That's right for ten lessons that you will
hear once a week for the next ten weeks.
We're going to take a look at an interview,
a job interview and we're going to take
you step by step throughout
the whole interview
process as well as
teaching you some useful
words and phrases that you can use next
time you're at a job interview in English.
Exactly, so pay
attention, today is the first
day we're going to
be entering the office
and we're going to
learn some things that are
important for talking to your future
employer or meeting people in an interview.
Come in.
Mr. Parsons?
Ah, you must be Rebecca, please do come in.
Thank you for making
some time to see me,
Mr. Parsons. It's a
pleasure to meet you finally.
The pleasure is all mine, Rebecca.
Have a seat please.
Now, would you like any
refreshments, tea or coffee?
A coffee would be
lovely, thank you.
Back, no sugar, no
problem. Sally, can we have
two coffees please,
one, no milk or sugar?
So, Rebecca, I understand you had a first
interview with Miss Child's last week?
Yes, that's correct. She filled me in on
the details of the job on the telephone.
Great. Well, I'm glad to
say she recommended
you for a second
interview and here we are.
Perhaps we can start by discussing
your background in resume details a little.
Yes, of course.
All right, we're back. So, now let's
take a look at language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So, one of the first things
that you're offered when
you go to interview at a
company is refreshments.
Right, would you like any refreshments?
This sounds complicated, but it's actually
a very simple word for beverages or drinks.
Right, so that's why he
offered her tea or coffee.
Right, so refreshments are cola,
coffee, tea, but how you answer this?
If I say would you like
any refreshments, Marco?
You can say, yes, water
would be fine, thank you.
Okay, water would be
fine or I'd like a Coke.
Or I'd like a cup of coffee, cup of coffee.
Great, refreshments are drinks.
And after that, the characters are
talking about the details of the job.
So, what are these details?
How are they different from the job itself?
Well, the details of the job are
the specific points about the job.
So, for example, if she applied
for a job as a receptionist,
the details of the job would
be answering the phones,
taking messages, receiving
people at the office.
Those are the main details of the job.
Also, we need someone
who works from 9am to 5pm.
Someone who is going
to come five days a week.
So, the details are basically more
information about something.
Right, the specific information
about a general topic.
And it's not only related to work, the
details can be of many, many things.
Right, so, if I ask you
about your details, Mark, will
you maybe tell me your
phone number, your address?
My phone name.
For a full name or birthday.
So, these are details.
Okay. And well, after they
talked about the details of the job.
After she explained that she received
the details of the job by phone,
Mr. Parsons says that Mr. Parsons said that
she was recommended for a second interview.
So, Rebecca is coming to
the office for a second time.
She already had one
interview and the woman
she talked to the first
time recommended her
for a second interview.
So, the verb here is to recommend.
Right, and you can recommend
a person, an object, a movie.
And that's basically
you are saying that this is
good and that it's worth seeing, it's
worth buying, it's worth interviewing.
For example, I really
like the movie Avatar.
Marco, I recommend you see it.
Okay, or I can say Catherine
recommended the movie Avatar.
Okay. So, Catherine
liked it, Catherine decided
Catherine suggested or
told Marco it would be good.
That's right. So, to recommend.
And then Mr. Parsons said that they're
going to start discussing her background.
Well, background think of the
word back, that means behind.
This usually means a
person's history at a job or
at many jobs or even their
educational background.
Information about where they studied.
That's right. So, the
background, maybe a person's
background is, as you
said, all their history,
work, study, many, many
different things, even
maybe seminars or
courses that they assisted.
Or even just their personal
history, for example,
Marco, you speak
English like an American.
What's your background?
Because I know you're not American.
Right, I'm from Ecuador.
Okay, background.
So, that means someone's personal history.
That's right. And hand
in hand with background,
we have a piece of
paper that usually you
send into an employer to apply for a job.
This is the famous resume.
Resume.
So, your right Marco resume is a document.
In this case, it is a document that lists
your work history, your working background.
And it's a very important
part of applying for a job.
And usually, you send your resume
before you go for the interview so that the
employer can look and
see, is this person qualified?
How old are they?
What's their work history?
And, well, very similar to a
resume, you may have heard a CV.
That's right, a CV is a lot like a resume.
It stands for Curriculum C, V-T-V-C-V.
And it's more detailed. It has more details
about a person's academic or study history.
Exactly. So, a resume,
I guess it's very similar
to a summary, a summary
of your work background,
whereas a CV will
have more details about
your education, maybe
more details about your
work background, what
did you do, objectives, etc.
Great. So, maybe I
should listen to today's
dialogue one more time.
And when we come back,
we'll be talking about some of the interesting
phrases we heard in today's dialogue.
Come in. Mr. Parsons?
Ah, you must be Rebecca. Please do come in.
Thank you for making
some time to see me,
Mr. Parsons. It's a
pleasure to meet you finally.
The pleasure is all mine, Rebecca.
Have a seat, please.
Now, would you like any
refreshments, tea or coffee?
A coffee would be
lovely. Thank you.
Black, no sugar. No problem.
Sally, can we have two coffees, please?
One, no milk or sugar.
So, Rebecca, I understand you had a first
interview with Miss Child's last week?
Yes, that's correct. She filled
me in on the details of the
job on the telephone.
Great. Well, I'm glad to say
she recommended you for a
second interview, and here we are.
Perhaps we can
start by discussing
your background in resume details a little.
Yes, of course.
All right, we're back. So,
now we have three phrases
that we're going to
take a look at on fluency
builder. Fluency
builder. All right, so when
Rebecca arrived, Mr. Parsons
said, "Ah, you must be
Rebecca, please do come
in." Okay, so you could
say, "Please come in."
This means, "Please come
into my office or
come on in." Right.
But here, the interesting
thing about this is the word
do. Right. He's using the verb
do, and it may sound wrong.
It may sound like it's unnecessary because
you do have a phrasal verb there already.
"Come in." So, you can
just say, "Please come in."
But when he says,
"Please do come in.
" He is emphasizing on
her to come in. That's right.
So, this is a very polite way
to invite someone inside.
You can also say,
"Please do have a seat."
All right. So, again,
you are emphasizing in a
very polite way to please
sit down. That's right.
Please do come in. So,
there are many other ways
that you can use it. So,
for example, if you really
want your friend to call
you sometime next time
you're in town, say, "Please do
call me next time you're in town.
" Please do. You could
even say it afterwards.
Simply, please do for emphasis.
Right. So, if I say,
"Hey, Catherine, I'm
going to call you next
time I'm in Shanghai.
" Please do. There you go.
So, that means, "Please do call.
" All right. So, please do
come in. Please do call.
All right. After that,
Rebecca says, "Thank you
for making some time
to see me, Mr. Parsons.
" So, she is happy that
Mr. Parsons is available
and wants to talk to her.
This is a very common
phrase that means, "Thank
you so much for interviewing
me." Right. So, I guess
it's kind of a way of
saying, "Look, I know that
you're a busy person and
that you don't have very
much time, so thank you
for making some
time to see me." Right.
So, this isn't just about
interviews. You could say this
phrase for meeting
with a client or meeting
with even a friend. You
could say, "Hey, Marco,
I know you were really
busy last week, but thank
you so much for making
some time to see me.
" Right. So, just basically
saying, "I understand
that you're very busy,
but I appreciate that
you made some time
to see me." All right.
And, well, she said, "You know what?
It's a pleasure to meet you, but Mr.
Parsons replied by saying, "The pleasure
is all mine." All right. Another very, very
polite phrase that you
hear a lot. Maybe some of
you have heard the phrase,
"It's a pleasure to meet
you before," but the
response, the answer, is
very interesting. The
pleasure is all mine.
So, this stands for,
"The pleasure is all mine.
" Right. And, I guess
it's the most appropriate
response if somebody
says, "It's a pleasure
to meet you," because
if you don't say this,
I think you may sound
a little bit arrogant.
Well, you could say, "It's a
pleasure to meet you, too.
" Right. But, this is
another way to answer the
person because you
don't always want to say,
"It's a pleasure to meet you."
It's a pleasure to meet you, too.
Right. This is a way
to say something
different and to say, "Well,
the pleasure is all mine.
" Right. But, it's very
important to answer something,
right, because if I
say, "It's a pleasure to
meet you," and you
say, "Thank you." It's like,
"No, that is a little bit arrogant." Right.
So, you have to say something. Right.
And, we recommend
that you say this or you just
say the same thing back.
So, it's nice to meet you.
Oh, it's nice to meet
you, too. Right. Okay.
And, our last phrase is
actually when they were talking
about, again, the details
of the job and she said that
Ms. Childs filled
her in on the details.
She said, "She filled me in on the
details of the job on the telephone.
" Okay. So, this is an interesting verb to
fill in or, in this case, to fill someone
in, to fill me in, to fill
you in. This basically
means to tell someone
about something. Right.
Or, if I know a little
bit of information,
but not a lot of information about
something, this way you're telling me more,
so I understand it better.
Right. I'm giving you
all the information. So,
maybe there is somebody
is talking about a rumor
in the office and you
go and you say, "Hey,
fill me in on the gossip.
" All right. So, you
want to know all about it.
Right. Or, for example,
Marco, we're having a party
next Sunday, but I'll
have to fill you in on the
details around Friday.
Okay. Because you don't have
all the information right now. Yeah, I
don't know yet what time or where. Okay.
So, to fill someone in is to
give them all the information
or to give them more
information. Fill me in.
Fill me in. All right.
Why don't we take a look
at our dialogue for the
last time and we'll be
back in a little bit. Come in. Mr. Parsons?
Ah, you must be Rebecca. Please do come in.
Thank you for making
some time to see me,
Mr. Parsons. It's a
pleasure to meet you finally.
The pleasure is
all mine, Rebecca.
Have a seat, please. Now, would you
like any refreshments, tea or coffee?
A coffee would be lovely. Thank
you. Black, no sugar. No problem.
Sally, can we have two coffees, please?
One, no milk or sugar.
So, Rebecca, I understand you had a first
interview with Miss Child's last week?
Yes, that's correct. She filled
me in on the details of the
job on the telephone.
Great. Well, I'm glad to say
she recommended you for a
second interview and here we are.
Perhaps we can
start by discussing
your background in resume details a little.
Yes, of course.
All right. So, as we
mentioned, this is the first
part of a 10-part series
of the interview series.
And this is going to
be very, very helpful.
As you saw in this first
part, we're just taking a look
at some basic vocab and
phrases that you can use
when you're just
introducing yourself.
You're just getting
started in the interview.
So, what we're going to
be looking at later on is
talking about yourself,
answering questions, but
many people don't
realize that one of the most
important parts of the
interview is very, very beginning.
Because some
psychologists say that we
make a decision about
a person or how we like a
person within the
first, I think, what?
30 seconds of talking to them.
Yeah. So, it's important that
you speak confidently
and that you speak some
say some of these English
phrases comfortably.
You know, it's a
pleasure to meet you.
Oh, it's the pleasure's mind. These little
things will really help you. That's right.
And I think as talking about
introductions and how this woman
arrived to the office,
I think one of the key
things that we would
recommend is to look at
that person in the eye and
give a firm handshake, right?
I don't know how many people
actually realize how important this is.
It's very, very important
because as an interviewer, the
person or the manager
who's interviewing you,
I think you can tell a lot from a person if
somebody gives you a very flimsy handshake,
or doesn't look you
in the eye. That's right.
Well, I think in many
ways, people think, Oh, this
person is not confident or
this person is uncomfortable
or this person is
hiding something.
And so, it's important really
to be yourself, to smile, to
look at a person in the
eyes, especially in a lot
of like American companies
or Canadian companies.
I know in other parts of
the world smiling with a
stranger is unusual or
maybe unacceptable.
But in America, it means
I'm confident. Here I am.
Here's my name. Nice to
meet you. It's a very important
part of an introduction.
Yes, very true.
So, we actually want
to hear what you think.
How important for you is a
handshake, a firm handshake,
looking someone in the
eye or how to interviews
work in your country. Let
us know. And we hope that
this is helpful for you
in the future if you're
looking for jobs or you just
want to practice your English.
That's right. So, if you have any
other questions or doubts, we're at
EnglishPod.com.
We'll see everyone there. Bye. Bye.